Hi, it's time for the EEVblog mailbag
and this turned up in the PO box. It's
from Elektor Electronics. I don't know
what's in here. I don't remember
ordering anything from them. Anyway, if
you want to send me stuff, there it is.
PO box 7949 Baulkham Hills, New South
Wales 2153
Australia.
No, I think that's an I. Anyway, let's
open it up
and check out what's inside.
Interesting.
Get the Swiss Army knife out.
Okay, what do we got in here?
Oh, it's a book.
It's a book.
Mastering the I squared C bus.
Yeah, excellent. Um,
okay.
Why? Let's have a look here.
Mastering the I squared C bus and EPS
something. What?
Okay.
Excellent.
Didn't order anything, but
there you go.
Commissioned by Vincent
Vincent Vincent Himpe. Thanks, Vincent.
I have no idea what's in here. Let's
have a look.
Oh, I got PCBs.
Tada!
Elektor Electronics and yeah, there it
is, Vincent Himpe. So, Vincent, author
of the book, has sent it to me.
Excellent. Thanks, Vincent. I'll check
it out. And these PCBs they're obviously
for example projects in the book. We've
got some real time clocks there. We've
got LCD keypad. we've got a scope
trigger, I squared prom, PWM leds.
What's that? It looks like some sort of
analog to digital converter maybe.
Um, and we've got whole other board.
Shame they don't actually give you the
parts to build it up, but sure you can
buy the
buy the parts, seven seg displays, all
that sort of thing.
Port expander by the looks of it. And 12
bit DAC, ADC, pots or digital pots, all
sorts of stuff. Neat. And obviously the
whole idea is to have this I squared C
system and build up
all these boards.
Ta-da. Oh. Yeah, it's um
Yeah, they've got
definitely got the uh
They they've got the individual PCBs
here. So, the whole thing looks like a
step-by-step
guide to building up these boards and
running through
all the They've got the schematics and
then running through all the I squared
all the commands and stuff like that to
control all these I squared C devices.
It actually looks
very well done. I like it. It's a
step-by-step example. So, if you're
after a step-by-step guide to learning
all about
I squared C historical background of I
squared C, it's got bills and materials,
parts references, all that sort of
stuff. There you go. It's looks like
it's part of this Lab Works with an X.
Get it? Concept straight from the lab to
your brain. It's a collection of books
each handling a particular topic in the
field of electronics. And this one is
the I squared C bus. And it does look uh
pretty good. It goes through all the
details of
how the bus works and
it's it's well done. It's well laid out.
I really
really like it at first glance. It's all
the timing stuff and things like that.
It's uh
looks
like Vincent's put a lot of work into
this and it's really well laid out.
Yeah.
I like it. If you really want to know
about I squared C,
looks like the go.
And another thing I got from Germany
from Tilman Boeman. So, thanks Tilman.
He's one of these
Nixie from Mr. Nixie. It's one of these
Nixie tube thermometer
kits. Very cool. Let's have a look at
it. They've got
nice plastic base here. They've
obviously probably you know laser cut
acrylic
base on the thing and a whole bunch of
whole bunch of parts.
And yep, there's tons of them and
there's the PCB in there. Looks pretty
good.
Let's take this out.
And there you go.
They've got a yellow
solder mask on that, which is rather
unusual. Kind of looks good though. Kind
of like it. And
yeah, I won't bore you with all the
parts, but apparently this is like not
microcontroller based. It's all passive
uh it's an entirely passive based
design.
Here's the
the thermometer index thing which the
Nixie tube goes in and they've got laser
cut on the back there. Yep, on the back
side they've got laser engraved on there
Fahrenheit and Celsius. Don't need
Fahrenheit.
What do you need that for? Hopeless
scale. But the idea is that I think this
lights up from the bottom. It sits in
the acrylic
base like that and lights up. And here
is our
Nixie tube. Aha, look at that.
Bar graph Nixie tube display.
Very nice. I like it. It's
X I don't think they're brand new. I
think they're like surplus Russian ones.
Although they could be actually brand
new, but I
think they're like old stock or
something like that. So
Russian
Nixie tube bar graph display. Real Cold
War stuff. Brilliant. I love it. So
thanks Tilman. That's excellent. I'm
going to enjoy building that one up and
I'll have to show you that when it's
finished. And that's what it looks like
when it's built up supposedly. And I
think it lights up blue or something
like that from the bottom. There's some
LEDs and it should look pretty funky. I
like it. Okay, so that's it. That's the
mailbag. If you want to send me stuff,
there's the address and
I'll
maybe if everyone likes this I'll turn
it into a regular segment where I just
open stuff cuz I know a lot of people
want to send me stuff for review and
things like that and
you know, I can't review everything but
maybe I can just open it up and give you
a little plug or something like that. If
you've got some sort of product. So
there you go. If you do, send it away.
Thanks. Catch you next time.